<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tri-Cities Area Real Estate Video Blog with Jerry Van Leeuwen</title>
    <description>Our mission at Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors is to be your best resource for Tri-Cities Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors, your professional Tri-Cities Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:32:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:32:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Helpful Tips and Tricks! </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Readers! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With new information about COVID-19 popping up every day, it can be hard to keep track of. So we thought, what better place to provide tips and resources than our blog; our readers are already here! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also want to encourage our readers to share any helpful tips or tricks with us that they’ve discovered so we can share those too! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-kids&quot;&gt;For the Kids! &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/KIDS BOOKS.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;302&quot; height=&quot;272&quot; /&gt;  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog-1--education-websites.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;289&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/zoo.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;609&quot; height=&quot;116&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-grown-ups&quot;&gt;For the Grown Ups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/fin.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;622&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;          New Updates: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/f-snip.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;598&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helpful-tips&quot;&gt; Helpful Tips &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/audible.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;298&quot; height=&quot;145&quot; /&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nikon.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;306&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dutchies.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;551&quot; height=&quot;94&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/kostya.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;661&quot; height=&quot;254&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you are all doing what you can to keep safe and we want you to know we’re here to help. Being a contributing part of our community is important to us, so if we can help, please just let us know! We’re all in this together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Safe Friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-------&quot;&gt;            &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/fb-review-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/g-review-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/helpful-tips-and-tricks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/helpful-tips-and-tricks.html</guid>
        
        <category>Covid Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>March Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KwH-uNLWtIc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in for our real estate market in March 2020. Although we had a strong start to the month, the declaration of a global pandemic certainly put a bit of a damper on things. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the latest stats and how they compare to what we saw during the same period in 2019:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;577 homes were sold (up 13.1%) for an average price of $583,000 (up 15.3%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;864 homes were listed (up 7.6%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;348 detached homes sold (up 7.1%) for an average of $679,000 (up 15.9%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;68 condos sold (up 5.1%) for an average of $378,000 (up 17.9%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 semis sold (up 4.2%) for an average of $492,000 (up 17.4%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;136 townhomes sold (up 17.2%) for an average of $457,000 (up 23%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the total number of homes available at the end of March was 535, which is down 35.9% from what we saw last year at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re implementing virtual showings, open houses, and more.%20http://localhost:4000/march-real-estate-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re implementing virtual showings, open houses, and more.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still seeing low inventory in our area, but also a lack of demand due to everyone being stuck in their homes. &lt;strong&gt;I believe that once this is over, there will be a lot of pent-up demand and the market will start humming back to normal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do need to buy and sell now, we’re doing everything in our power to help while also keeping your health and safety at the top of our minds. We’re implementing virtual showings, Zoom meetings, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about real estate or need real estate assistance of any kind, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 14:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/march-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/march-real-estate-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can We Do for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xp-6UU70ffg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’re doing well and keeping safe. We ask that if there is anything we can do to help you or your loves ones, please just let us know. Real estate-related or not, our team is always here for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of focusing on the unfortunate COVID-19 pandemic that’s currently upon us, we thought we would check in to see what our friends have been up to and see what you’re doing with your newfound wealth of time. We would like to believe there is a silver lining to everything, and maybe this is nature’s way of reminding us to take the time to enjoy the things we love. Perhaps spend some more time focusing on the things we care about. Our team has been fortunate enough to spend some extra time with our families while still being able to help our clients reach their goals, because here at VLA, that’s something we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’ve taken some time toput together a plan so that we may better serve our clients through these unusual circumstances while still respecting guidelines and doing our part to flatten the curve. Check out our video to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to also say a huge thank you to everyone working on the front lines for their efforts. From nurses and doctors to grocery store clerks and truck drivers, we see the sacrifices being made to help keep this country running. Time away from their families, longer work hours; some can’t even go inside of their own homes without putting their families at risk. So, from the bottom of our hearts we need to say thank you for your services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, real estate-related or not, please let us know if there’s a way we can help you and your families get through these strange times. We are here to help support our community always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe, friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 14:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-we-do-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-we-do-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wendy Black Interiors Stages Your Home Perfectly</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1l2N-VX6Isg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently met with Wendy Black of Wendy Black Interiors, a preferred vendor of Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her business, which she started 12 years ago, focuses primarily on home staging and staging consultations. If you’re a home seller in need of a dinette set or certain pieces to compliment your originals, Wendy and her team can add to it or do a full-furnishing if you have a vacant house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wendy’s work is absolutely and consistently amazing! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At her warehouse (check out a tour at 0:51), Wendy has an extensive array of artwork—everything from large to small, abstracts to florals. During a consultation, Wendy assesses a seller’s decor and cross-references it with her vast inventory to find perfect matches. Her pieces are so tasteful that oftentimes sellers arrange to buy something similar for their new homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Wendy Black Interiors gives sellers an edge by setting an attractive, radiant, and comfortable atmosphere within their home.%20http://localhost:4000/wendy-black-interiors-stages-your-home-perfectly.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Wendy Black Interiors gives sellers an edge by setting an attractive, radiant, and comfortable atmosphere within their home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Wendy, the newest trend in interior decor is a general move away from glass and chrome, though they’re still useful in particular situations. On the other hand, warm woods are very popular right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does she manage her massive collection, constantly setting up pieces in homes and taking them down soon after it sells? Wendy credits her exceptional, speedy staff, some of which have worked for her for the past five years; &lt;strong&gt;they can set up an entire house in a couple of hours. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wendy Black Interiors gives sellers an edge by setting an attractive, radiant, and comfortable atmosphere within their home. If you’re a seller wanting to get in touch with Wendy and her team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wendyblackinteriors.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit her website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and browse their portfolio; further contact information is listed there as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate questions for me, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I love hearing from you and helping in whatever way I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 13:58:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wendy-black-interiors-stages-your-home-perfectly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wendy-black-interiors-stages-your-home-perfectly.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>January Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RDRUU34nSpg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 started off a little slow; we only sold 281 residential properties out of the 464 that were listed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of detached homes listed is down 19% from this time in 2019. The number of condos listed has increased by 18.2% from this time last year. The number of semi-detached houses listed was about the same as from this time in 2019. The number of townhomes listed was up 7.9% from this time last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The average sale price was up 15.7% in January.%20http://localhost:4000/january-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The average sale price was up 15.7% in January.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average sale price compared to January 2019 was up 15.7%, at $561,000. Overall the number of properties listed in the Waterloo region compared to this time last year was down by 21.1%, so &lt;strong&gt;we’re seeing a very strong demand for homes.&lt;/strong&gt; This is causing prices to increase dramatically. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or real estate in general, please feel free to give us a call or send an email to getresults@vanleeuwenadvisors.com. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 14:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/january-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/january-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Path to the Good Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kJugF6nXMNQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 19, Sai Lee of The Mortgage Guys and I are hosting The Path to the Good Life, and you’re invited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This event will answer three important financial questions that keep people up at night:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you pay off your mortgage in 10 years—or in half the time of a regular 25- or 30-year mortgage?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you pay off your children’s education in full? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you build extra wealth for retirement on top of everything else you’re doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This event is intended for anyone who’s curious about getting into the market.%20http://localhost:4000/the-path-to-the-good-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This event is intended for anyone who’s curious about getting into the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sai will use numbers from real-life examples addressing each of these questions. He’ll also cover different types of investment; he’ll tell you what those investments are, and why some are better than others. For example, we’ll delve into the strategy of putting your money into buying a business, the share market, and real estate investments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is intended for anyone who’s curious about getting into the market, whether you’re a first-time homebuyer or your average household investor. These are concepts anyone can learn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To RSVP, give us a call or email us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vanleeuwenadvisors@gmail.com&quot;&gt;vanleeuwenadvisors@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; We will also be sending out invites VIA Eventbrite so make sure to keep an eye out for it! We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-path-to-the-good-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-path-to-the-good-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Maximize Your Holiday Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mR1MVF0-0KQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are four quick tips to remember if you plan on listing your home during the holiday season:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Decorate the house.&lt;/strong&gt; With the holiday season in full swing, your home is likely already in good condition, but don’t go overboard with your decorations. Stick to a classier look. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Hire the right agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your agent communicates with you directly throughout the holidays and doesn’t just disappear when you need them. You can also coordinate your schedules so you don’t have to show your home during important times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure your agent communicates with you directly throughout the holidays.%20http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-maximize-your-holiday-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure your agent communicates with you directly throughout the holidays.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Give buyers a place to escape the cold.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s snowing out, have the heat turned up, play some soft music in the background, and set the tone once they walk into your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have a great video tour and marketing campaign for your home.&lt;/strong&gt; There might be fewer buyers out there right now, but good social media marketing will capture their attention, and they’ll be able to see a 360-degree tour of your home before they see it in person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about selling during the holidays or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 11:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-maximize-your-holiday-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-maximize-your-holiday-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's Our 5-Year Anniversary!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mOrl-XBsPqU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WINTER IS COMING! Joking aside, we’re pretty sure it’s already knocking at the front door as you read our newsletter! This hasn’t stopped us from keeping super busy helping our clients with their home goals, though. The past month has been action packed with handling listings and getting our buyers into their new homes. To read about some of what we’ve been up too, scroll down to see some of our client success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As most of you may not know, November officially marks the Van Leeuwen Advisors team’s anniversary. This means we have been proudly serving the KW region for five wonderful years! We would like to say thank you to each and every one of you for their continued support. Without you, we couldn’t be here! We are so grateful to be connected to so many wonderful people. Our priority and focus here at Van Leeuwen Advisors is always on our clients. We work for them to make sure we give them the best experience we possibly can. It has and will always be the driving force to which our reputation has been built on: Hard work and dedication to our people. Be sure to check out our video below to hear from our fearless team leader about some things we’ve discovered in this crazy world of real estate within the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know how hectic things can get and how packed daily schedules become with the holiday season arriving, so we wish you the best of luck starting your holiday shopping and remind everyone to drive safe out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, we are here anytime to answer any questions you may have about buying, selling or investing so don’t hesitate to give us a call or send an email our way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe on those roads friends and we’ll chat soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your Family Realtor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/its-our-5-year-anniversary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/its-our-5-year-anniversary.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect from a Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5sNc9GCkivk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homebuyer in today’s market and you’re purchasing either your first home or a move-up home, having the home inspected is definitely to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home inspection will give you a good scope of the home’s condition and provide a basis on which to estimate the cost of any repairs that will need to be done down the road. What sorts of repairs most often come up on an inspection report?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The roof&lt;/strong&gt;—What is the age, condition, and life expectancy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heating and air conditioning&lt;/strong&gt;—Does it function properly? When was it last serviced?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structural integrity&lt;/strong&gt;—Did the previous owners do any renovations? Were those done to code?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;—Are there any cracks in the foundation that could potentially allow water to seep in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt;—What are their ages, conditions, and life expectancies?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walls&lt;/strong&gt;—Some inspectors will use an infrared camera to look through the walls to see if there are any cold spots that might suggest water leakage or weak spots in the insulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With any resale home, there are bound to be a few issues that come up on the inspection report, like reasonable wear and tear from the previous owner. At the end of the day, it’s up to your discretion to renew the terms of the transaction and move forward to the closing table after receiving the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to purchase a home in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’ll be happy to walk you through the process of a home inspection and set clear expectations about what kinds of repairs the home you purchase will need down the road. Hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-expect-from-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-to-expect-from-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Protect Your Home This Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AAiWtOmDhGk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall is here and winter is coming. With that being said, here are a few tips to help you prepare your home to have a calm winter and a more pleasant spring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Check your HVAC and have it serviced.&lt;/strong&gt; Replace your filter, too! If you have an older thermostat, it might be time to consider switching to a programmable thermostat to save you a few bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Inspect your windows and doors.&lt;/strong&gt; If there are cracks or air leaks, recaulk before winter to save even further on those heating costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Clean out your gutters.&lt;/strong&gt; Gutters that are clogged lead to water build-up and ice damming. This is definitely something you don’t want in the middle of winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Clogged gutters can lead to ice damming and leaks.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-home-this-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Clogged gutters can lead to ice damming and leaks.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Reverse your ceiling fans.&lt;/strong&gt; By reversing your fans, it will push the warm air from your furnace down to keep your living spaces warmer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Turn off your exterior water taps.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve learned this the hard way. Hearing something burst in the wall during a cold night could lead to an explosion like it did for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or if you’re thinking about buying or selling a home anytime soon, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-home-this-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-home-this-winter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
