<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambridge Real Estate Podcast with Jerry Van Leeuwen</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors - your professional Cambridge Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Jerry Van Leeuwen</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-03-06 14:08:36 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Jerry Van Leeuwen</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>GetResults@VanleeuwenAdvisors.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Cambridge Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors - your professional Cambridge Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wendy Black Interiors Stages Your Home Perfectly</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wendy-black-interiors-stages-your-home-perfectly.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-25 13:58:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/Wendy+Black+Interiors+Stages+Your+Home+Perfectly.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently met with Wendy Black of Wendy Black Interiors, a preferred vendor of Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors. 

Her business, which she started 12 years ago, focuses primarily on home staging and staging consultations. If you’re a home seller in need of a dinette set or certain pieces to compliment your originals, Wendy and her team can add to it or do a full-furnishing if you have a vacant house. 

Wendy’s work is absolutely and consistently amazing! 

At her warehouse (check out a tour at 0:51), Wendy has an extensive array of artwork—everything from large to small, abstracts to florals. During a consultation, Wendy assesses a seller’s decor and cross-references it with her vast inventory to find perfect matches. Her pieces are so tasteful that oftentimes sellers arrange to buy something similar for their new homes. 

“Wendy Black Interiors gives sellers an edge by setting an attractive, radiant, and comfortable atmosphere within their home.”

According to Wendy, the newest trend in interior decor is a general move away from glass and chrome, though they’re still useful in particular situations. On the other hand, warm woods are very popular right now. 

How does she manage her massive collection, constantly setting up pieces in homes and taking them down soon after it sells? Wendy credits her exceptional, speedy staff, some of which have worked for her for the past five years; they can set up an entire house in a couple of hours. 

Wendy Black Interiors gives sellers an edge by setting an attractive, radiant, and comfortable atmosphere within their home. If you’re a seller wanting to get in touch with Wendy and her team, visit her website and browse their portfolio; further contact information is listed there as well. 

As always, if you have any real estate questions for me, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I love hearing from you and helping in whatever way I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/Wendy+Black+Interiors+Stages+Your+Home+Perfectly.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/Wendy+Black+Interiors+Stages+Your+Home+Perfectly.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I took a tour of Wendy Black Interiors’ warehouse and talked to Wendy herself about the latest decor trends. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I took a tour of Wendy Black Interiors’ warehouse and talked to Wendy herself about the latest decor trends. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>January Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/january-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-13 14:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/January+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

2020 started off a little slow; we only sold 281 residential properties out of the 464 that were listed. 

The number of detached homes listed is down 19% from this time in 2019. The number of condos listed has increased by 18.2% from this time last year. The number of semi-detached houses listed was about the same as from this time in 2019. The number of townhomes listed was up 7.9% from this time last year. 

“The average sale price was up 15.7% in January.”

The average sale price compared to January 2019 was up 15.7%, at $561,000. Overall the number of properties listed in the Waterloo region compared to this time last year was down by 21.1%, so we’re seeing a very strong demand for homes. This is causing prices to increase dramatically. 

If you have any questions about our market or real estate in general, please feel free to give us a call or send an email to getresults@vanleeuwenadvisors.com. We would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/January+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/January+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the latest numbers from our Waterloo region real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the latest numbers from our Waterloo region real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Path to the Good Life</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-path-to-the-good-life.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-28 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/The+Path+to+the+Good+Life.mp4</guid>
        <description>

On March 19, Sai Lee of The Mortgage Guys and I are hosting The Path to the Good Life, and you’re invited!

This event will answer three important financial questions that keep people up at night:


  How do you pay off your mortgage in 10 years—or in half the time of a regular 25- or 30-year mortgage?
  How do you pay off your children’s education in full? 
  How do you build extra wealth for retirement on top of everything else you’re doing?


“This event is intended for anyone who’s curious about getting into the market.”

Sai will use numbers from real-life examples addressing each of these questions. He’ll also cover different types of investment; he’ll tell you what those investments are, and why some are better than others. For example, we’ll delve into the strategy of putting your money into buying a business, the share market, and real estate investments. 

This event is intended for anyone who’s curious about getting into the market, whether you’re a first-time homebuyer or your average household investor. These are concepts anyone can learn. 

To RSVP, give us a call or email us at vanleeuwenadvisors@gmail.com. We will also be sending out invites VIA Eventbrite so make sure to keep an eye out for it! We hope to see you there!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/The+Path+to+the+Good+Life.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2020/The+Path+to+the+Good+Life.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I want to invite you to an event that will answer your most important financial questions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I want to invite you to an event that will answer your most important financial questions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Maximize Your Holiday Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-maximize-your-holiday-home-sale.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-12 11:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/4+Tips+to+Maximize+Your+Holiday+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are four quick tips to remember if you plan on listing your home during the holiday season:

1. Decorate the house. With the holiday season in full swing, your home is likely already in good condition, but don’t go overboard with your decorations. Stick to a classier look. 

2. Hire the right agent. Make sure your agent communicates with you directly throughout the holidays and doesn’t just disappear when you need them. You can also coordinate your schedules so you don’t have to show your home during important times. 

“Make sure your agent communicates with you directly throughout the holidays.”

3. Give buyers a place to escape the cold. If it’s snowing out, have the heat turned up, play some soft music in the background, and set the tone once they walk into your home. 

4. Have a great video tour and marketing campaign for your home. There might be fewer buyers out there right now, but good social media marketing will capture their attention, and they’ll be able to see a 360-degree tour of your home before they see it in person. 

If you have questions about selling during the holidays or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/4+Tips+to+Maximize+Your+Holiday+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/4+Tips+to+Maximize+Your+Holiday+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you selling your home this holiday season? Here are four tips that will help you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you selling your home this holiday season? Here are four tips that will help you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It's Our 5-Year Anniversary!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/its-our-5-year-anniversary.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-25 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Dear friends,

WINTER IS COMING! Joking aside, we’re pretty sure it’s already knocking at the front door as you read our newsletter! This hasn’t stopped us from keeping super busy helping our clients with their home goals, though. The past month has been action packed with handling listings and getting our buyers into their new homes. To read about some of what we’ve been up too, scroll down to see some of our client success stories.

As most of you may not know, November officially marks the Van Leeuwen Advisors team’s anniversary. This means we have been proudly serving the KW region for five wonderful years! We would like to say thank you to each and every one of you for their continued support. Without you, we couldn’t be here! We are so grateful to be connected to so many wonderful people. Our priority and focus here at Van Leeuwen Advisors is always on our clients. We work for them to make sure we give them the best experience we possibly can. It has and will always be the driving force to which our reputation has been built on: Hard work and dedication to our people. Be sure to check out our video below to hear from our fearless team leader about some things we’ve discovered in this crazy world of real estate within the last five years.

We know how hectic things can get and how packed daily schedules become with the holiday season arriving, so we wish you the best of luck starting your holiday shopping and remind everyone to drive safe out there!

As always, we are here anytime to answer any questions you may have about buying, selling or investing so don’t hesitate to give us a call or send an email our way!

Stay safe on those roads friends and we’ll chat soon!

Van Leeuwen Real Estate AdvisorsYour Family Realtor
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We would like to say thank you to everyone for their continued support.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We would like to say thank you to everyone for their continued support.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect from a Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-expect-from-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12 13:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+to+Expect+from+a+Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a homebuyer in today’s market and you’re purchasing either your first home or a move-up home, having the home inspected is definitely to your advantage.

A home inspection will give you a good scope of the home’s condition and provide a basis on which to estimate the cost of any repairs that will need to be done down the road. What sorts of repairs most often come up on an inspection report?


  The roof—What is the age, condition, and life expectancy?
  Heating and air conditioning—Does it function properly? When was it last serviced?
  Structural integrity—Did the previous owners do any renovations? Were those done to code?
  Foundation—Are there any cracks in the foundation that could potentially allow water to seep in?
  Windows—What are their ages, conditions, and life expectancies?
  Walls—Some inspectors will use an infrared camera to look through the walls to see if there are any cold spots that might suggest water leakage or weak spots in the insulation.


With any resale home, there are bound to be a few issues that come up on the inspection report, like reasonable wear and tear from the previous owner. At the end of the day, it’s up to your discretion to renew the terms of the transaction and move forward to the closing table after receiving the report.

If you’re looking to purchase a home in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’ll be happy to walk you through the process of a home inspection and set clear expectations about what kinds of repairs the home you purchase will need down the road. Hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+to+Expect+from+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+to+Expect+from+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m covering the topic of home inspections—what you can expect to find during the process as well as what can be negotiated. Learn more here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m covering the topic of home inspections—what you can expect to find during the process as well as what can be negotiated. Learn more here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Protect Your Home This Winter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-home-this-winter.html</link>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-23 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/How+to+Protect+Your+Home+This+Winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Fall is here and winter is coming. With that being said, here are a few tips to help you prepare your home to have a calm winter and a more pleasant spring:

1. Check your HVAC and have it serviced. Replace your filter, too! If you have an older thermostat, it might be time to consider switching to a programmable thermostat to save you a few bucks.

2. Inspect your windows and doors. If there are cracks or air leaks, recaulk before winter to save even further on those heating costs.

3. Clean out your gutters. Gutters that are clogged lead to water build-up and ice damming. This is definitely something you don’t want in the middle of winter.

“Clogged gutters can lead to ice damming and leaks.”

4. Reverse your ceiling fans. By reversing your fans, it will push the warm air from your furnace down to keep your living spaces warmer. 

5. Turn off your exterior water taps. I’ve learned this the hard way. Hearing something burst in the wall during a cold night could lead to an explosion like it did for me.

If you have any questions for me or if you’re thinking about buying or selling a home anytime soon, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/How+to+Protect+Your+Home+This+Winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/How+to+Protect+Your+Home+This+Winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s that time of year where you should start preparing your home for the cold weather that’s coming. Here are five quick, easy things you can do to get started.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s that time of year where you should start preparing your home for the cold weather that’s coming. Here are five quick, easy things you can do to get started.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Know About Our Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-you-know-about-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-13 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+Should+You+Know+About+Our+Real+Estate+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The latest real estate numbers are in from the month of September so I wanted to bring them to you as we start October. 

Some of these numbers are absolutely insane. For example, we had 526 residential sales in September, which is up 17.7% from last year. At the same time, residential listings were down by 2.1%.

“Detached home sales are up by 20.4% over the last year.”

For detached homes, we had 330 home sales last month. That’s up by 20.4%. The number of condo sales, however, were down by 24%. Townhome sales were up by 34.4% and semi-detached sales were up by 10%.

Overall, the average sale price is actually up 10.2% from this time last year and now sits at $541,850. The average prices for detached homes, townhomes, and semi-detached homes all increased by double digits, while the price for condos increased by just 3%.

If you have any questions for me about any of these numbers or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+Should+You+Know+About+Our+Real+Estate+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/What+Should+You+Know+About+Our+Real+Estate+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The latest numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you today. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The latest numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you today. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Quick Tips for Paying Down Your Mortgage Faster</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-quick-tips-for-paying-down-your-mortgage-faster.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-30 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/3+Quick+Tips+for+Paying+Down+Your+Mortgage+Faster.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you first get your mortgage, the majority of your payment goes toward your interest. However, there are ways to pay down the principal of your loan more quickly, and today we’ll cover three of the most effective methods:

“If the rate you locked in originally is significantly higher than rates are right now, it may make sense to refinance your mortgage.”

1. Round up your mortgage payments. If you had a $543 bi-weekly payment, for example, upping your payment to $600 would add an extra $14,000 toward your mortgage over time. This would shave years off of the life of your loan. 

2. Put any extra money you come into toward your loan. If you get a tax break, for example, adding those funds to your loan could reduce your term by a year or more.

3. Refinance when interest rates are low. Currently, interest rates are at historic lows. And with lower rates come lower monthly payments. Therefore, if the rate you locked in originally is significantly higher than rates are right now, it may make sense to refinance your mortgage. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/3+Quick+Tips+for+Paying+Down+Your+Mortgage+Faster.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/3+Quick+Tips+for+Paying+Down+Your+Mortgage+Faster.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Paying down your mortgage more quickly is possible, and today we’ll share three tips that help you do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Paying down your mortgage more quickly is possible, and today we’ll share three tips that help you do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Ask Before Hiring a Realtor</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-should-ask-before-hiring-a-realtor.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-16 16:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Robert+Dekanski/What+You+Should+Ask+Before+Hiring+a+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Year to date, 9,716 homes have been listed in our market, but only 6,116 of those listings actually sold. This means 33% of all homes in our local market have failed to sell. Why has this happened? 

My guess is that, in many instances, those homes failed to sell because they were being represented by the wrong agent. This just goes to show how important your choice of Realtor really is when the time comes for you to sell, and the key to choosing the right agent is to ask the right questions before you hire them. Here are a few questions you should pose to any agent you’re thinking of working with: 

1. “How many months of inventory are available in my area compared to the overall region?” Questions like this will not only help you to understand market conditions, but will also help you gauge how knowledgeable an agent is. In addition to explaining local inventory by area, the agent should also be able to break down inventory levels by price point.

“A truly outstanding agent will have some unique qualities that set them apart from the common Realtor.”

2. “What kind of marketing strategy will you use for my home?” The way your agent presents your property to the market could make or break your success. If they’re planning to solely rely on antiquated methods like newspaper ads, for example, you may want to work with someone else. It isn’t that newspaper advertising is bad; it’s just that the right agent should use multiple channels, including modern ones like social media, to maximize your home’s exposure.

3. “What training events have you attended to continue your education as an agent?” In real estate, continued education is key. Simply having a real estate license isn’t enough. The right agent for you and your home sale is one who stays current with the latest best practices.

4. “How much time will you spend prospecting?” Putting your home on the multiple listing service and hoping buyers take notice isn’t enough. The agent you hire should be one who is proactive in seeking out interested buyers for your property. 

5. “What makes you stand out from other agents?” It goes without saying that a truly outstanding agent will have some unique qualities that set them apart from the common Realtor, and knowing what these qualities are, specifically, could guide you to making the right decision for your home sale. 

In addition to the questions we’ve listed today, we’ve got many more listed in our exclusive seller’s magazine. So if you have any other questions, would like a copy of our seller’s magazine, or are curious how my team and I can help you meet (and exceed) your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Robert+Dekanski/What+You+Should+Ask+Before+Hiring+a+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Robert+Dekanski/What+You+Should+Ask+Before+Hiring+a+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Before you hire an agent to help you sell your home, there are five critical questions you should ask them first.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Before you hire an agent to help you sell your home, there are five critical questions you should ask them first.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/preparing-your-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-03 14:38:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Preparing+Your+Home+for+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re gearing up to list your home soon, there are a few tips to keep in mind if you want to sell quickly and for top dollar. 

First, declutter the home. This means clearing off your countertops and making sure you have clean surfaces throughout the home. If buyers see clutter lying around, it will distract them from making an emotional connection to your home. 

Along with decluttering, you need to depersonalize the home. Remember, you want buyers to visualize themselves living in your home—not seeing who lives there now. Take down any family photos and try replacing them with some artwork or more generic photos. 

“Along with decluttering, you need to depersonalize the home.”

Next, have a contractor or handyman visit your home and give it a good once-over. You never know—there may be spots that need to be repainted or trim that needs repair. Buyers notice little items like these, and taking care of them will help your home stand out among the competition. 

Also, consider getting a pre-inspection for your home. I’ve had several clients get higher offers with fewer conditions specifically because buyers knew their home had a pre-inspection. The home inspector will make sure your home’s not hiding any potential deal-killers that will cause the deal to fall apart after the buyer has already gone under contract. A pre-inspection also gives you the chance to fix any issues beforehand, which saves you money in the long run because you won’t have to worry about taking money off the sale price if the buyer discovers any issues. 

After that, it’s time to hire a professional stager to stage the home. We include a staging consultation in our services, and stagers will be able to advise you on furniture placement, wall decor, paint colors, decluttering and depersonalization, etc. They’ll have your home in the best shape possible when the time comes to take listing photos and videos. 

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Preparing+Your+Home+for+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Preparing+Your+Home+for+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are certain surefire tips you must follow if you want to maximize your home sale.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are certain surefire tips you must follow if you want to maximize your home sale.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your 2019 End-of-Summer Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-2019-end-of-summer-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-16 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Your+2019+End-of-Summer+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re nearing the end of summer, so it’s time to take a quick look at how our 2019 summer market is doing as we wrap things up. 

This year, we’ve seen a high level of demand for homes priced at $600,000 or less—a sign that we’re still feeling the effects of the “stress test” we faced in 2018. Right now, we have about two to three months’ worth of inventory below the $500,000 range, and we see that number rise to between five and six months of inventory in the $500,000-to-$700,000 range. And with homes priced higher than $700,000, inventory shoots up to about eight months’ worth.           Keep in mind that the Bank of Canada did just lower the qualifying rate to 5.19%, which helped to kickstart more activity among first-timers and in some of the lower price points. In a nutshell, lower-priced homes are still selling strong.   

Why is this important information for both buyers and sellers? 

Starting with buyers, it’s important to understand what you can expect given current market conditions. For instance, if you’re a first-time buyer and you’re entering the market for a $400,000 to $500,000 home, odds are that we’ll see some pretty stiff competition and multiple offers above asking price. 

“No matter your goals, my team and I are here to help.”

The good news is that we’ll likely find homes that have spent a longer-than-normal amount of time on the market, which will allow us to negotiate for favorable terms. If we find ourselves in a multiple-offer situation, we can employ certain tactics to give ourselves an edge over the competition (e.g., a personal letter to the seller, preemptive inspections, etc.). 

On the seller side, if you’re pricing your home between $300,000 and $600,000, we’ll see a flurry of buyer activity. But because buyers are being a bit picky right now, it’s paramount that we still price at market value. 

On our team, we offer different strategies for pricing your home to bring as many buyers as possible to your door and potentially initiate a multiple-offer situation. No matter your goals, we’re here to help. 

If you have any questions about our current market or about buying, selling, or investing in real estate, feel free to contact me personally at Jerry@VanLeeuwenAdvisors.com or by calling us at 519-772-4328. We look forward to serving your needs!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Your+2019+End-of-Summer+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jerry+Van+Leeuwen/Videos/2019/Your+2019+End-of-Summer+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s the very latest on our summer real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jerry Van Leeuwen</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s the very latest on our summer real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cambridge, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Jerry Van Leeuwen</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Jerry Van Leeuwen</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Van Leeuwen Real Estate Advisors - your professional Cambridge Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
